# Nicholas Christiny

# Software Developer

■ nchristiny@gmail.com

nchristiny.com

**♀** Chicago, IL

**y** chileannick

in nchristiny

**o** nchristiny

### Skills

Java

Ruby

**JavaScript** 

SQL

MongoDB

**PostgreSQL** 

Rails

React

HTML5

CSS3

Sass

jQuery

webpack

Mocha

**Jasmine** 

Rspec

AWS

JIRA

Git

Linux

# **Projects**

Watch This!

A film recommendation engine API built on a lightweight Rails-API MongoDB back end and React front end using webpack. Testing performed with Rspec and Mocha.

Chord Explorer

Single page app deployed to Heroku from greenfield in 8 days. The app shows songs that can be played given the user's choice of chords. It uses JavaScript library Raphaël to render SVG images of guitar chords within AJAX partial views using data from a PostgreSQL back end.

Background in open-source, object-oriented software development. Experienced in agile methodology and deploying responsive web app and pages.

## **Employment**

Customer Hero SpotHero Inc.

Chicago, IL Apr 2017 to Dec 2017

- Superhero-level customer support at fast-based mobile parking app startup.
- Monitor site status and outages and liaise with QA as needed.
- Document and escalate emerging issues via Salesforce.

Apprentice Software Engineer Jellyvision Inc.

Chicago, IL

Feb 2016 to May 2016

- Build recommendation engine API with React and Rails 5-API and MongoDB.
- Learn to use SOLID design principles on production codebase.
- Complete greenfield project creating internal company dashboard tool.
- Test in real-time using Karma, Mocha, Chai, Guard, Rspec.
- Engage in weekly sprint planning and retrospectives with stakeholders.
- Track progress using JIRA and Agile methodology.
- Work closely with QA, DevOps for continuous integration issues.

AppleCare Support Advisor

Apple Inc.

Austin, TX

Nov 2012 to May 2015

- Resolve diverse bilingual account and technical issues.
- Train and mentor new advisors.
- Protect customer and company confidentiality.
- Worked as contractor in position from December 2011 to October 2012.

Account and Technical Service Representative

Austin, TX

Blizzard Entertainment Inc.

Jan 2010 to Sep 2011

- Achieve first contact resolution and key performance indicators consistently.
- $\bullet \ \, {\sf Troubleshoot} \ \, {\sf diverse} \ \, {\sf operating} \ \, {\sf systems}, \, {\sf hardware} \ \, {\sf and} \ \, {\sf software} \ \, {\sf configurations}. \\$

Front End Web Developer

Austin, TX

Harte-Hanks Inc.

Sep 2009 to Dec 2009

- Design small business WordPress sites via client-facing consulting, HTML, CSS.
- Deploy using PHP, mySQL, FTP.

Process Engineer - Diffusion

Austin, TX

Freescale Semiconductor Inc.

Ian 2006 to Nov 2008

• Utilize statistical process control and 5S Lean manufacturing techniques.

#### Education

Dev Bootcamp - Chicago

Accelerated web development program 2015

University of Texas at Austin

**B.S.** Astronomy

#### **Awards**

Apple Inc. · Recognition for Outstanding Customer Support

Apr 2013

Apple Inc. · Employee of the Quarter Nominee

Aug 2012

## Volunteering

Dev Bootcamp · Mentor Chicago Current

Provide code reviews and feedback to assist students in computational thinking.

FreeGeek Chicago · Volunteer

Current

Chicago

Refurbish hardware with open-source software and provide community education.